<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arkaprabha Chakraborty</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Arkaprabha Chakraborty</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© ArkaprabhaChakraborty</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics of Security - Part 1 (Theory notes made by googling and reading different articles)</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/basics_of_security_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/basics_of_security_1/</guid><description>What is Computer Security? Computer security is the protection of items of value, called assets, of a computer or computer system. There are many types of assets, involving hardware, software, data, process, staff, or a combination thereof.
Computer security: Integrates into the Assets Life Cycle: Security begins with acquiring assets. It is important that there is a chain of custody for the physical assets, up to and including when the asset is powered on.</description></item><item><title>Basics of Security - Part 2 (Theory notes made by googling and reading different articles)</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/basics_of_security_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/basics_of_security_2/</guid><description>Classes of Attackers White Hat A white hat hacker breaks security for non-malicious reasons, perhaps to test their own security system or while working for a security company which makes security software. The term &amp;ldquo;white hat&amp;rdquo; in Internet slang refers to an ethical hacker. This classification also includes individuals who perform penetration tests and vulnerability assessments within a contractual agreement. Black Hat A black hat hacker is a hacker who violates computer security to be malicious or for personal gain.</description></item><item><title>HTB Web Challenge walkthrough with OWASP ZAP: Templated</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/templated_htb_web_challenge_zap_walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/templated_htb_web_challenge_zap_walkthrough/</guid><description>So I decided to take the Hack The Box(HTB) Web Challenges with OWASP ZAP. This blog is a walkthrough of the &amp;ldquo;Templated&amp;rdquo; web challenge in HTB, shout out to clubby789 for creating this challenge.
What is ZAP? Zed Attack Proxy (ZAP) is the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular open source web application scanner. ZAP is free to use and tons of different add-ons are available to extend its functionality. Even though ZAP is officially called a &amp;ldquo;web application scanner&amp;rdquo;, we, the contributors and the core team of ZAP, sometimes unofficialy call it an &amp;ldquo;Integrated Hacking Environment (IHE)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Fundamentals Part-1</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/postgres_fundamentals_part_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/postgres_fundamentals_part_1/</guid><description>Introduction PostgreSQL was created in 1985 by Micheal Stonebraker. The name came from &amp;ldquo;Post&amp;rdquo;-Ingress. It is a free software which is really easy to learn. You can install postgresql on your system by following the docs or this blog. For starters we use the university dataset from kaggle. This has a simple schema but lot&amp;rsquo;s of data which is kinda useful for practicing indexing.
Creating the database Login to your postgresql interactive terminal using the following bash command:</description></item><item><title>All of my blogs :)</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/all_of_my_blogs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/all_of_my_blogs/</guid><description>These are all of my blogs till now in an organised manner. All of these are some &amp;ldquo;first thought&amp;rdquo; blogs, which I decided I should be sharing with you all :). Why this blog post? Well I could have spent some time and configured a breadcrumb page, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t wanna do that. It would have slowed me down :). That being said, the code to my portfolio is open source [Wow what a surprise :P] and if you are looking to make your first PR you can just start by creating a breadcrumb page for this blog :)</description></item><item><title>Setup a lovely little portfolio with hugo</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/portfolio_with_hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/portfolio_with_hugo/</guid><description>Hugo is an amazing tool. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful static site generator that can be used to create a beautiful websites. Hugo, is world&amp;rsquo;s fastest static website engine. What I like about Hugo is it&amp;rsquo;s speed and flexibility.
For my blog I can just use some simple Markdown files, and Hugo build the site for me. This helps me to create a blog that is easy to manage. For starters I followed the Hugo quick start tutorial to setup a my portfolio website.</description></item></channel></rss>