<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arkaprabha Chakraborty</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Arkaprabha Chakraborty</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© ArkaprabhaChakraborty</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The OWASP Top 10 (Theory notes made by googling and reading different articles)</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/owasp_top_10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/owasp_top_10/</guid><description>What is OWASP Top 10? Well it&amp;rsquo;s simply a list of top 10 web application security vulnerabilities. The link to the actual source material has been given already, so you can read more about it there. The list was last updated in 2021. Many security researchers including the very best in OWASP Foundation believe it&amp;rsquo;s still relevant in that order, even tho I kinda disagree :P.
Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s get started with the list.</description></item><item><title>The CIA Triad ♺</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/cia_triad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/cia_triad/</guid><description>NOPE it&amp;rsquo;s not the CIA who watches us all, the open, friendly yet closed, confidential, epitome of ahem ahem ahem :P. The CIA triad is a set of three basic principles of information security: confidentiality, integrity, and availability. These three principles are the foundation of information security and are the basis for all security policies, standards, procedures, and guidelines. The CIA triad is also known as the &amp;ldquo;Holy Trinity&amp;rdquo; of information security.</description></item><item><title>The Networking Essentials</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/networking_essentials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/networking_essentials/</guid><description>This is kinda a sub-blog within my main blog. This is a collection of notes I&amp;rsquo;ve taken while studying for the CCNA. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll ever take the exam, but I did learn a lot and some cool badges which will probably go away in a few years :).
Networking knowledge is one of the most basic skills you must have before embarking on &amp;ldquo;H4c!&amp;lt;in6&amp;rdquo;, or start your DevOps or Development journey.</description></item><item><title>Where to start?? DevOps Basics - Part 4</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_4/</guid><description>Analyze your application portfolio (Application Portfolio Analysis) It&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon for large enterprises to have hundreds of applications in all forms and shapes using different underlying technologies, buisness processes and DevOps capabilities. The wise way to invest your time and money wisely is to perform an application portfolio analysis (APA), to identify which applications should be focused on.
There are 4 dimesions of an APA. For each category you collect the data and you translate it into a relative graph.</description></item><item><title>Where to start??? DevOps Basics - Part 5</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_5/</guid><description>Find your MVC Minimum viable cluster (MVC) is a subset of applications that are the most important to the business and are the best candidates for a DevOps transformation. Improving the MVC leads to faster and more reliable delivery of business value.
Thge concept behind this is that of a weakest link in a chain. the weakest link in a chain defines the overall doability of a chain. Similarly the applicatiion witth lowest maturity in a cluster tends to define oyour ability to deliver.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Basics - Part 3</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_3/</guid><description>The 3 dimensions of Enterprise DevOps For DevOps at enterprise level, there are 3 dimensions that need to be considered. These are:
Technology People and Process Ecosystem Technology In this dimension, you need to cover things like:
Test Automation Cloud Technologies Breaking up of Monolihtic applications and architectures The Speed at which one can deliver value is dependent on the agility and how nimble the architecture is.</description></item><item><title>Value Stream Maps (VSM) DevOps Basics - Part 6</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_6/</guid><description>What is a VSM? A value stream map is a popular tool for DevOps transformation. Basically it is a flowchart like technique which identifies all the relevant application and systems and visualize the end to end delivery process. It provides a visibilty of work for the organization. You can create a value stream map by gathering stakeholders from every part of the product development value stream: the business line, design, testing, QA, operations, and support.</description></item><item><title>Corporate culture and it's roles - DevOps Basics - Part 2</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_2/</guid><description>What is an organization&amp;rsquo;s culture? Organization&amp;rsquo;s culture is like a shadow of the organization. The processes, behaviour and tools used by the organization shape it&amp;rsquo;s culture, just like a person&amp;rsquo;s clothing, dressing sense and body language shapes them. This &amp;ldquo;shadow&amp;rdquo; cannot be changed directly and abruptly, without changing the &amp;ldquo;object&amp;rdquo; casting the &amp;ldquo;shadow&amp;rdquo;.
To change culture, we need to change the organization&amp;rsquo;s processes, behaviour and tools. This is a long term process and requires a lot of effort and time.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Basics - Part 1</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/devops_basics_1/</guid><description>What is DevOps? DevOps is the combination of cultural philosophies, practices, and tools that increases an organization’s ability to deliver applications and services at high velocity.
The main purpose of DevOps is to boost developer productivity.
Under DevOps model, the operations team is no longer isolated. Sometimes, the two teams, ie, the development team and operations team are merged into a single team where the engineers work across the entire application lifecycle, from development and test to deployment to operations, and develop a range of skills not limited to a single function.</description></item><item><title>Basics of Security - Part 1 (Theory notes made by googling and reading different articles)</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/basics_of_security_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/basics_of_security_1/</guid><description>What is Computer Security? Computer security is the protection of items of value, called assets, of a computer or computer system. There are many types of assets, involving hardware, software, data, process, staff, or a combination thereof.
Computer security: Integrates into the Assets Life Cycle: Security begins with acquiring assets. It is important that there is a chain of custody for the physical assets, up to and including when the asset is powered on.</description></item><item><title>Basics of Security - Part 2 (Theory notes made by googling and reading different articles)</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/basics_of_security_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/basics_of_security_2/</guid><description>Classes of Attackers White Hat A white hat hacker breaks security for non-malicious reasons, perhaps to test their own security system or while working for a security company which makes security software. The term &amp;ldquo;white hat&amp;rdquo; in Internet slang refers to an ethical hacker. This classification also includes individuals who perform penetration tests and vulnerability assessments within a contractual agreement. Black Hat A black hat hacker is a hacker who violates computer security to be malicious or for personal gain.</description></item><item><title>HTB Web Challenge walkthrough with OWASP ZAP: Templated</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/templated_htb_web_challenge_zap_walkthrough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/templated_htb_web_challenge_zap_walkthrough/</guid><description>So I decided to take the Hack The Box(HTB) Web Challenges with OWASP ZAP. This blog is a walkthrough of the &amp;ldquo;Templated&amp;rdquo; web challenge in HTB, shout out to clubby789 for creating this challenge.
What is ZAP? Zed Attack Proxy (ZAP) is the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular open source web application scanner. ZAP is free to use and tons of different add-ons are available to extend its functionality. Even though ZAP is officially called a &amp;ldquo;web application scanner&amp;rdquo;, we, the contributors and the core team of ZAP, sometimes unofficialy call it an &amp;ldquo;Integrated Hacking Environment (IHE)&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Fundamentals Part-1</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/postgres_fundamentals_part_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/postgres_fundamentals_part_1/</guid><description>Introduction PostgreSQL was created in 1985 by Micheal Stonebraker. The name came from &amp;ldquo;Post&amp;rdquo;-Ingress. It is a free software which is really easy to learn. You can install postgresql on your system by following the docs or this blog. For starters we use the university dataset from kaggle. This has a simple schema but lot&amp;rsquo;s of data which is kinda useful for practicing indexing.
Creating the database Login to your postgresql interactive terminal using the following bash command:</description></item><item><title>All of my blogs :)</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/all_of_my_blogs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/all_of_my_blogs/</guid><description>These are all of my blogs till now in an organised manner. All of these are some &amp;ldquo;first thought&amp;rdquo; blogs, which I decided I should be sharing with you all :). Why this blog post? Well I could have spent some time and configured a breadcrumb page, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t wanna do that. It would have slowed me down :). That being said, the code to my portfolio is open source [Wow what a surprise :P] and if you are looking to make your first PR you can just start by creating a breadcrumb page for this blog :)</description></item><item><title>Setup a lovely little portfolio with hugo</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/portfolio_with_hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/portfolio_with_hugo/</guid><description>Hugo is an amazing tool. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful static site generator that can be used to create a beautiful websites. Hugo, is world&amp;rsquo;s fastest static website engine. What I like about Hugo is it&amp;rsquo;s speed and flexibility.
For my blog I can just use some simple Markdown files, and Hugo build the site for me. This helps me to create a blog that is easy to manage. For starters I followed the Hugo quick start tutorial to setup a my portfolio website.</description></item><item><title>HTTP and HTTPS Basics - How the internet works</title><link>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/http_basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://arkaprabhachakraborty.github.io/blog/http_basics/</guid><description>HTTP (HyperText Transfer Protocol) Most internet communications are made with web requests through the HTTP protocol. HTTP is an application-level protocol used to access the World Wide Web resources. The term hypertext stands for text containing links to other resources and text that the readers can easily interpret.
HTTP communication involves a client sending a request for a resource to a server, which then processes the request and returns the resource.</description></item></channel></rss>